Process Improvement and the Role of Measurement
Welcome back to this session on the power of measurement. As you can see,
I have a simple little line marked here, with beginning point and an end point.
My question is, I’d like for you to describe this line for me.
Think of a way to describe it without numbers, without measurements.
My, it becomes a difficult task.
One naturally and intuitively says, well how long is the line?
This is why we have rulers.
See we have a standard inch. And I can measure this line.
And if I do so, it looks to me to be
three and a quarter inch.
Let's really tighten in on this point right here.
Right there, we’re gonna really tighen in on that. Okay,
we can see that it's three and a quarter inches wide.
three and one quarter inch.
Now, we know that a line is the shortest distance between two points.
And we described that line in a standard inch. See this 1 inch is a standard.
There sits an inch over in a vault in England.
That's the standard from which all rulers and everything else is based.
And of course, the inch is arbitrary. It could've been a googlelog, whatever that may be.
But nonetheless, we have a measurement here, three and a quarter inches.
And that measurement. You know there is a simple saying that we’ve got.
Let the data
do the talking.
I can't over emphasize the power of that thought.
Let the data do the talking because, you know, data speaks very loud.
Data is management by fact.
Management by fact.
We don't manage by circumstance. We don't manage by opinion.
We don't manage by the seat of our pants. We manage by fact.
And let me tell you, fact equals data.
Because it's verifiable. It’s repeatable. Recall, we talked about verifiable knowledge.
So, three and a quarter inches is verifiable knowledge.
When I asked for a description about this line, it’s verifiable.
This person here, can take this ruler,
and verify that line.
So, can the next person and the next person.
So, that when we all say it's three and a quarter inches.
You can see there's little variation between people.
So, these people all have the same knowledge.
That's what's great about measurements. They all carry the same knowledge.
Where again, if you didn't have this, if that was unknown,
then the knowledge about that line would be different.
Far greater difference, between these three individuals,
than if we did have the measurements.  So again, we let the data do the talking.
Management by fact. So simply recall, once again.
At the risk of beating a dead horse to death, and that's okay in this case.
Because it's a really valuable horse. Y is a function of X.
If we can't measure Y and we can't measure X, then the actions that we take,
the knobs in our processes that we go twist. How do we know the effect that that has on Y?
Unless, here's Y, a scale of Y,
and here's the range of operation of Y, before we twist knob X.
So, this is before. See, and this is after.
Well notice there is some overlap here. Yeah, that overlap represents uncertainty.
I don't know whether twisting knob X.
If I see a data point occur there. X is the reason for that or not.
The more that these two separate,
the more certainty I have that X is the causal variable with respect to Y.
But see once again, unless I can quantify Y.
And say what the measurements of Y are, for each occurrence of Y.
Unless I let the data do the talking. Unless I manage the situation by fact, by data.
Then all I have is intuitive, experiential, knowledge
of the effect of X on Y. So we want to scientifically
be able to identify the vital few X’s out there.
And what their consequential impact is on Y, so I can prioritize them for process control reasons.
That's why this idea of measurement
is so important. And why the idea,
of let the data do the talking for the product or the service. Doesn't matter.
Measurements are measurements, they apply equally.
It's an equal opportunity employer so to speak.
The numbers don't care whether they come from a service process, or
from a commercial process. Measurements are measurements.
And that's why they're so important.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.